<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: releases | Rollbar - Blog - real-time error tracking for Rails, Python, PHP, Javascript, and Flash]]></title>
  <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/blog/categories/releases/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-08T17:29:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://rollbar.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rollbar, Inc.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resolving Rollbar Items in Versions]]></title>
    <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/09/17/resolving-rollbar-items-in-versions/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T09:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/09/17/resolving-rollbar-items-in-versions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We just rolled out a new feature to help track which versions/revisions errors are resolved in. When resolving items within Rollbar, you have the option of entering a revision or version number. If one is entered, it will appear in the item's status history to let anyone looking at the item better understand specifically when it was fixed.</p>

<p>This version can be combined with a new <code>code_version</code> parameter set in the configuration options of the latest versions of our notifiers. This can be set to either a numerical value (eg. 1, 24, 300), a semantic version value (eg. 1.0.3, 2.9), or a git revision sha. Here are examples on how to set this parameter in our JavaScript and Ruby notifiers:</p>

<p>In the <a href="https://github.com/rollbar/rollbar.js">JavaScript</a> snippet:
```javascript
_rollbarParams = {</p>

<pre><code>// ... other configuration
"client.javascript.code_version": "bdd2b9241f791fc9f134fb3244b40d452d2d7e35"
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>In your <a href="https://github.com/rollbar/rollbar-gem">rollbar-gem</a> configuration:
```ruby
Rollbar.configure do |config|</p>

<pre><code># ... other configuration
config.code_version = 'bdd2b9241f791fc9f134fb3244b40d452d2d7e35'
</code></pre>

<p>end
```</p>

<p>The other notifiers have a very similar top-level code_version configuration settings. See the notifier readmes for more info.</p>

<p>If you resolve an item within Rollbar in a certain version and are also specifying a <code>code_version</code> for your code, we will use both of these values to decide whether or not to reactivate the item.</p>

<p>For example, say you have a bug in version 1.0 of your app. The bug is fixed and will be deployed to users in verision 1.1, but that won't happen for a few days. You can just resolve the Rollbar item associated with this bug now, but also specify that the resolved version is 1.1. You will no longer get reactivation notifications for this item until occurrences of this item with a <code>code_version</code> >= 1.1 come in.</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/resolve-in-version-popup.png"></p>

<p>If you connect Rollbar with GitHub, this process will also work with Git SHAs. We'll query the GitHub API to determine whether one commit is a parent of the other.</p>

<h2>Auto-resolving items in GitHub commits</h2>

<p>You can now also include Rollbar item tags in your GitHub commit messages to automatically resolve them in the correct revision when deploying. Just include one of the following strings in your commits for each item you want to resolve:</p>

<ul>
<li>fix $ref</li>
<li>fixed $ref</li>
<li>fixes $ref</li>
<li>resolve $ref</li>
<li>resolved $ref</li>
<li>resolves $ref</li>
<li>close $ref</li>
<li>closed $ref</li>
<li>closes $ref</li>
</ul>


<p>Where $ref is one of the following item tags:</p>

<ul>
<li>Full item URL, eg. <code>https://rollbar.com/item/123456789</code></li>
<li>Item ID, eg. <code>rb#123456789</code></li>
<li>Short item ID, eg. <code>rb#22</code> This appears at the top left of an item page.</li>
</ul>


<p>Then execute a deploy by hitting the <a href="http://rollbar.com/docs/deploys_bash/">deploy API endpoint</a>. The items referenced in any of the commit messages of the deploy will be resolved using the respective revision of that commit.</p>

<p>You can start tracking and resolving errors in Rollbar by <a href="https://rollbar.com/signup">signing up for free</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[jQuery Error Instrumentation]]></title>
    <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/08/08/jquery-error-instrumentation/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-08T11:18:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/08/08/jquery-error-instrumentation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we are releasing a new feature for our JavaScript notifier that should make tracking down errors much easier if you use jQuery 1.7 and above. The new functionality comes in a separate JS plugin snippet that should be placed right below where jQuery is loaded. Here is the first version of the plugin:</p>

<p>```html</p>

<script>
!function(r,n,e){var t={"notifier.plugins.jquery.version":"0.0.1"};n._rollbar.push(
{_rollbarParams:t});r(e).ajaxError(function(r,e,t,u){var o=e.status;var a=t.url;
n._rollbar.push({level:"warning",msg:"jQuery ajax error for url "+a,jquery_status:o,
jquery_url:a,jquery_thrown_error:u,jquery_ajax_error:true})});var u=r.fn.ready;
r.fn.ready=function(r){return u.call(this,function(){try{r()}catch(e){
n._rollbar.push(e)}})};var o={};var a=r.fn.on;r.fn.on=function(r,e,t,u){
var f=function(r){var e=function(){try{return r.apply(this,arguments)}catch(e){
n._rollbar.push(e);return null}};o[r]=e;return e};if(e&&typeof e==="function"){
e=f(e)}else if(t&&typeof t==="function"){t=f(t)}else if(u&&typeof u==="function"){
u=f(u)}return a.call(this,r,e,t,u)};var f=r.fn.off;r.fn.off=function(r,n,e){
if(n&&typeof n==="function"){n=o[n];delete o[n]}else{e=o[e];delete o[e]}
return f.call(this,r,n,e)}}(jQuery,window,document);
</script>


<p>```</p>

<p>The source can be found on GitHub <a href="https://github.com/rollbar/rollbar.js/blob/master/src/plugins/jquery.js">here</a>.</p>

<p>The snippet wraps the <code>ready()</code>, <code>on()</code> and <code>off()</code> functions in jQuery to wrap any passed-in handlers in try/except blocks to automatically report errors to Rollbar. This lets us collect the full stack trace with line and column numbers for each frame, instead of just the last frame with only a line number. When combined with <a href="https://rollbar.com/docs/guides_sourcemaps/">source maps</a>, this makes debugging JavaScript errors much more doable.</p>

<p>The new snippet also adds a handler to ajaxError() to automatically report any jQuery AJAX errors such as 404s and 500s to Rollbar. If you don't want this, add the following option to your base snippet's <code>_rollbarParams</code>:
<code>
"notifier.plugins.jquery.ignoreAjaxErrors": true
</code>
You can start tracking errors in Rollbar by <a href="https://rollbar.com/signup">signing up for free</a>. Or read more in the <a href="https://rollbar.com/docs/notifier/rollbar.js">docs</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debug Production Errors in Minified JS with Source Maps and Rollbar]]></title>
    <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/07/25/debug-production-errors-in-minified-javascript-with-source-maps-and-rollbar/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-25T14:49:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/07/25/debug-production-errors-in-minified-javascript-with-source-maps-and-rollbar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://rollbar.com">Rollbar</a> just got a much-requested feature: Source Maps support for Javascript. If you minify your Javascript code in production, this will make debugging production errors much easier. This feature is now live for all accounts.</p>

<h2>What Are Source Maps?</h2>

<p>If you minify your Javascript code (i.e. using <a href="https://github.com/mishoo/UglifyJS2">UglifyJS2</a> or the <a href="https://developers.google.com/closure/compiler/">Closure Compiler</a>), it gets harder to debug errors. Stack traces reference the line/column numbers in the minified code instead of the original source code.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/developertools/sourcemaps/">Source Maps</a> were designed to resolve this; they provide a mapping back from the minified line/column numbers to the original code. Chrome and Firefox have tools to use them in development, but what about errors that happen in production?</p>

<h2>Source Maps and Rollbar</h2>

<p>Rollbar can now map stack traces that reference minified code back to the original source files, lines, and column numbers. Here's what a stack trace might have looked like before:</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/stacktrace-minified.png"></p>

<p>Here's the de-minified version:</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/stacktrace-unminified.png"></p>

<p>We'll also use the de-minified stack trace in our <a href="https://rollbar.com/docs/guides_grouping/">grouping algorithm</a>, which should result in more useful grouping.</p>

<h2>Getting this set up</h2>

<p>To get started, you'll need to make a change to <code>_rollbarParams</code> in the on-page javascript snippet. Add the following two parameters:</p>

<p><code>javascript
_rollbarParams = {
  // ... existing params ...
  // set this to 'true' to enable source map processing
  "client.javascript.source_map_enabled": true,
  // provide the current code version, i.e. the git SHA of your javascript code.
  "client.javascript.code_version": "bdd2b9241f791fc9f134fb3244b40d452d2d7e35"
}
</code></p>

<p>Next, either:
- Add a sourceMappingUrl comment at the end of your minified file to point to the source map
- Upload the source map (along with all source files) separately, as part of your deploy process</p>

<p>This second step is a bit more involved so please see our <a href="https://rollbar.com/docs/guides_sourcemaps/">docs</a> for more details.</p>

<h2>Caveats</h2>

<p>All of this relies on having a stack trace with line and column numbers. Unfortunately, browser support for column numbers is inconsistent. As of today, this will work in Chrome, Firefox, and IE10+, and only for caught errors reported like this:</p>

<p><code>javascript
try {
  doSomething();
} catch (e) {
  _rollbar.push(e);
}
</code></p>

<p>Uncaught errors (reported via window.onerror) don't have column numbers in any browser we're aware of, so they aren't able to be de-obfuscated. For best results, catch all your exceptions so you don't fall back to the top-level error handler.</p>

<p>Happy debugging and please don't hesistate to contact us (<a href="team@rollbar.com">team@rollbar.com</a>) if you have any questions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Release Roundup]]></title>
    <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/05/29/may-release-roundup/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-29T15:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/05/29/may-release-roundup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here's a roundup of what's new at Rollbar in the month of May.</p>

<h3>Big Features</h3>

<p>We revamped our notifications system, and added integrations with a bunch of new services. Rollbar now works with <a href="http://asana.com">Asana</a>, <a href="http://campfirenow.com/">Campfire</a>, <a href="https://flowdock.com">Flowdock</a>, <a href="https://github.com/features/projects/issues">Github Issues</a>, <a href="http://hipchat.com">Hipchat</a>, <a href="http://jira.com">JIRA</a>, <a href="http://pivotaltracker.com">Pivotal Tracker</a>, and <a href="http://trello.com">Trello</a>, as well as any arbitrary system via a <a href="http://www.webhooks.org/">Webhook</a>. See the <a href="https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/05/06/rules-engine-for-notifications-campfire-hipchat-jira-trello/">announcement blog post</a> for more details.</p>

<h3>Small Features</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>You can now customize how occurrences are grouped. This first release allows you to define rules of things that should always be grouped together. See the documentation: <a href="https://rollbar.com/docs/guides_custom_grouping/">Custom Grouping Rules</a>. An in-depth post on how to use this is coming soon.</p></li>
<li><p>There's now a "Download CSV" link at the bottom of the Items page, which will let you download a CSV of what you see on the page. Note that this information is also available via our <a href="https://rollbar.com/docs/test_console/">API</a>.</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/download-csv.png"></p></li>
<li><p>You can now sort the Items page by Total Occurrences or Unique Users, in additon to Last Occurrence. Click on the column headers to change the sort.</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/item-list-sort.png"></p></li>
<li><p>Links to files in Github are now linked to the appropriate revision, when this information is available. We'll use one of the following (trying each in order):</p>

<ul>
<li>the value of <code>server.sha</code></li>
<li>the value of <code>server.branch</code>, if it looks like a SHA</li>
<li>the revision from the last deploy before the first occurrence of the item</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3>Library Updates</h3>

<h4>Ruby</h4>

<p>We released <a href="https://github.com/rollbar/rollbar-gem">rollbar-gem</a> versions 0.9.11 through 0.9.14. The changes include a fix for use with Rails 4, a concurrency bugfix, better support for JSON requests, and the ability to include custom metadata with all reports. See the full <a href="https://github.com/rollbar/rollbar-gem/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md">changelog</a> for details. To upgrade, change the rollbar line in your Gemfile to:</p>

<p><code>ruby
gem 'rollbar', '~&gt; 0.9.14'
</code></p>

<p>We also contributed a fix to <a href="https://github.com/CrowdFlower/resque-rollbar">resque-rollbar</a> to force use of synchronous mode when reporting Resque failures (instead of async mode, which doesn't play nicely with Resque).</p>

<h4>Python</h4>

<p><a href="https://github.com/rollbar/pyrollbar">pyrollbar</a> gained a feature and now at version 0.5.7. See the <a href="https://github.com/rollbar/pyrollbar/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md">changelog</a> for details.</p>

<h3>Bug Fixes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where pressing the back button would sometimes cause Chrome to render one of our JSON responses as if it were HTML</li>
<li>Fixed a bug where removed email addresses could not be re-added</li>
</ul>


<h3>Documentation Updates</h3>

<ul>
<li>Added guide on how our <a href="https://rollbar.com/docs/guides_grouping/">grouping algorithm</a> works.</li>
<li>Cleaned up our <a href="https://rollbar.com/docs/api_items/">Items API Reference</a> and fixed a few outdated parts</li>
</ul>


<p>More is on the way. Stay tuned! And don't forget to send us any feedback: <a href="mailto:team@rollbar.com">team@rollbar.com</a> &mdash; we love hearing from you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rules Engine for Notifications, Plus Integrations with Campfire, Hipchat, JIRA, and Trello]]></title>
    <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/05/06/rules-engine-for-notifications-campfire-hipchat-jira-trello/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T21:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/05/06/rules-engine-for-notifications-campfire-hipchat-jira-trello</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we're revamping the model for defining what you want to be notified about from <a href="https://rollbar.com">Rollbar</a>. Rollbar now integrates with <a href="http://asana.com">Asana</a>, <a href="http://campfirenow.com/">Campfire</a>, <a href="https://github.com/features/projects/issues">Github Issues</a>, <a href="http://hipchat.com">Hipchat</a>, <a href="http://jira.com">JIRA</a>, <a href="http://pivotaltracker.com">Pivotal Tracker</a>, and <a href="http://trello.com">Trello</a>, as well as any arbitrary system via a <a href="http://www.webhooks.org/">Webhook</a>.</p>

<h2>New Integration Channels</h2>

<p>In addition to our existing channels (Email, Asana, Github Issues, Pivotal Tracker, and Webhook), we're launching support for four more: Campfire, Hipchat, JIRA, and Trello. You can set up all of this in Settings -> Notifications.</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/integration-channels.png"></p>

<h2>Notification Rules Engine</h2>

<p>Notifications are now configured per-project (instead of per-user-per-project), using a trigger-action model. There are triggers for the following events:</p>

<ul>
<li>New Item (first occurrence of a new issue)</li>
<li>Reactivated Item (a previously resolved issue has occurred again)</li>
<li>10<sup>nth</sup> Occurrence (an issue has occurred for the 10th, 100th, etc. time)</li>
<li>Resolved Item (an item has been resolved by hand)</li>
<li>Reopened Item (an item has been reopened by hand)</li>
<li>Post-deploy (you've notified us that you deployed a new release)</li>
</ul>


<p>Corresponding actions are available for most actions in most channels. If it would make sense, it probably exists.</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/rules-engine.png"></p>

<p>Most actions can be configured as you'd expect (i.e. set which teams should receive an email, or which user to assign JIRA issues to).</p>

<p>Item-related triggers can be filtered by environment, level, title (exception class+message), and filename. Deploy triggers can be filtered by environment and comment. Our underlying tech supports much more than the UI exposes, so let us know what other filters you'd like to see.</p>

<h2>Migration for existing customers</h2>

<p>We've migrated existing customers' settings to the new system, but there were a few aspects that didn't map very well (i.e. per-user-per-project settings). We hope the new system is easier to use for most use-cases and still workable for complex setups, but let us know if there's something you are having trouble doing.</p>

<h2>Questions? Feedback?</h2>

<p>Let us know if you have any questions about how to get the notifications you want. We look forward to your feedback. What other integrations do you want? Let us know in the comments, or email us at <a href="mailto:team@rollbar.com">team@rollbar.com</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
