<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: javascript | Rollbar - Blog - real-time error tracking for Rails, Python, PHP, Javascript, and Flash]]></title>
  <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/blog/categories/javascript/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-07T14:11:09-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://rollbar.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rollbar, Inc.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript and Source Maps in a Django App]]></title>
    <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/08/02/javascript-and-source-maps-in-a-django-app/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-02T11:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/08/02/javascript-and-source-maps-in-a-django-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's pretty well known that every web app needs frontend JavaScript these days to provide the best possible user experience. You are probably going to have a bunch of JavaScript files that need to be loaded by your users for that to happen, and since we all care about performance, minifiying and compressing these files is an absolute must. But what happens when it comes time to debug issues in these minified files? Stack traces will more or less be completely useless. How do we solve this problem?</p>

<p>JavaScript source maps solve this problem. They allow you to map a point in a minified file back to the unminfied source, making it possible to actually identify and fix issues encountered in a production app environment.</p>

<p>Below I have outlined a simple guide for setting up source map generation and usage in a sample Django app. You'll learn how generate source maps for minified files, debug errors that happen in these files, and also a quick overview of what's required to get this working for your production environments.</p>

<h2>Local Debugging with Source Maps</h2>

<p>Say you have a simple Django app with the following directory structure:</p>

<pre><code>...
app/
    ...
    views.py
    static/
        js/
            site.js (containing various models and functionality used in your app)
            jquery.js (unminified)
            util.js
    templates/
        index.html
</code></pre>

<p><code>site.js</code> would have the following code:
```javascript
var aFunction = function() {</p>

<pre><code>var a = b;
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>App = {};
App.errorCausingFunction = function() {</p>

<pre><code>aFunction();
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p><code>views.py</code> would just contain one view that rendered <code>index.html</code>, and here is how <code>index.html</code> would look like:
```html
...</p>

<script src="static/js/site.js"></script>


<script src="static/js/jquery.js"></script>


<script src="static/js/util.js"></script>


<p>....</p>

<script>
    App.errorCausingFunction();
</script>


<p>...
```</p>

<p>Let's minify. Start by installing UglifyJS2:</p>

<pre><code>npm install -g uglify-js
</code></pre>

<p>Here is an example command run from <code>app/</code> that will generate minified Javascript:</p>

<pre><code>uglifyjs static/js/site.js static/js/jquery.js static/js/util.js --output static/js/all.min.js
</code></pre>

<p>Here we are using uglifyjs to minify three JS files, <code>site.js</code>, <code>util.js</code> and <code>jquery.js</code>, into <code>all.min.js</code>.</p>

<p>Update your <code>index.html</code> to include only <code>all.min.js</code>:
```html</p>

<script src="static/js/all.min.js"></script>


<p>```</p>

<p>Now let's try navigating to <code>index.html</code> and seeing what happens:</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/stacktrace-minified-chrome.png"></p>

<p>Not the most helpful stack trace. All the line numbers are 1, and if this were a much larger file with more generic function/variable names, it would be completely useless in helping you debug where things went wrong.</p>

<p>Let's introduce source map functionality to our app.</p>

<p>Modify your minification command to look like this:</p>

<pre><code>uglifyjs static/js/site.js static/js/jquery.js static/js/util.js --output static/js/all.min.js --source-map static/js/all.min.map --source-map-url /static/js/all.min.map
</code></pre>

<p>Here we are adding two new options, <code>--source-map</code> and <code>--source-map-url</code>. UglifyJS2 will now generate the resulting source map as <code>static/js/all.min.map</code>, and will append a comment to the end of the minified file containing the url to the source map on your website, in this case <code>/static/js/all.min.map</code>. Note, you may need to modify the comment in <code>all.min.map</code> to read <code>//#</code> instead of <code>//@</code>, as this is a <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/mozilla.dev.js-sourcemap/4uo7Z5nTfUY">recently new convention</a>.</p>

<p>Now navigate to your app in Chrome with Developer Tools open. If everything is set up right, Chrome will automatically translate the frames in the stack trace to the unminified equivalents, like so:</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/stacktrace-unminified-chrome.png"></p>

<p>Note that the filenames and line numbers now refer to the original source code, instead of the minified source.</p>

<h2>Production Debugging with Source Maps</h2>

<p>The above process is all fine and dandy for errors encountered on your local machine, but what if you want to keep track of errors encountered by your users in real-time?</p>

<p>Here at <a href="https://rollbar.com">Rollbar</a>, we have recently reworked our error processing pipeline to support the application of source maps on JavaScript errors. Here's how you would get Rollbar hooked up and reporting from your production environment:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Create a Rollbar account</p></li>
<li><p>Follow the instructions to insert the Rollbar Javascript notifier snippet into your base template</p></li>
<li><p>Modify the snippet configuration to signal that source maps should be used:
<code>javascript
_rollbarParams = {
// ... other params ...
// set this to 'true' to enable source map processing
"client.javascript.source_map_enabled": true,
// provide the current code version, i.e. the git SHA of your javascript code.
"client.javascript.code_version": "bdd2b9241f791fc9f134fb3244b40d452d2d7e35"
}
</code></p></li>
<li><p>Make sure your minified files link properly to publicly accessible source maps using the <code>sourceMappingURL</code> comment:
<code>javascript
// ... minified js file contents ...
//# sourceMappingURL=&lt;url for source map&gt;
</code></p></li>
</ol>


<p>Now, when your app sends Rollbar an error report, Rollbar will automatically attempt to download source maps defined in your minified files and apply them to stack frames located in these files.</p>

<p>Here is an example of the source map application process in action with an unminified stack trace that you would see in Rollbar:</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/stacktrace-unminified-rollbar.png"></p>

<p>Notice the unminified source filenames with relevant line and column numbers.</p>

<h2>Automating things</h2>

<p>It's a bit annoying to have to minify everything every time you change one of your Javascript files. We have a small script set up here in our dev environments that uses <a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/MacFSEvents">macfsevents</a> to listen for Javascript file changes. Once such events occur, we check to see if only the Javascript files we care about are affected. If so, we run an <code>uglifyjs</code> command on all the Javascript files to generate minified sources and source maps.</p>

<p>You can even go one step further by making an API call to Rollbar to upload your source map as part of your deploy process. This API endpoint also accepts source file uploads for files referenced by the source map, giving us the ability to print out the unminified source code for each frame in the stack trace. For example:</p>

<p><img src="https://d37gvrvc0wt4s1.cloudfront.net/static/img/blog/stacktrace-unminified-rollbar-with-source.png"></p>

<p>Here's a sample command you could use to upload a source map and source file to our API:</p>

<p><code>bash
curl https://api.rollbar.com/api/1/sourcemap \
-F access_token=aaaabbbbccccddddeeeeffff00001111 \
-F version=bdd2b9241f791fc9f134fb3244b40d452d2d7e35 \
-F minified_url=http://127.0.0.1:8005/static/js/all.min.js \
-F source_map=@app/static/js/all.min.map \
-F app/static/js/site.js=@app/static/js/site.js
</code></p>

<p>The last param is a mapping of source file path to actual source file contents. The path would need to match the one defined in your source map, generated by your minification tool.</p>

<h2>More info</h2>

<p>Check out the documentation for more info about integrating your <a href="https://rollbar.com/docs/notifier/rollbar.js/">JavaScript</a> and <a href="https://rollbar.com/docs/guides_sourcemaps/">source maps</a> with Rollbar. Rollbar also integrates with your Python, Rails, PHP and Node.js based backends.</p>

<p>Contact us at <a href="team@rollbar.com">team@rollbar.com</a> if you have any questions, and be sure to follow <a href="https://twitter.com/rollbar">@rollbar</a> for more updates regarding new releases!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Async node.js API server testing]]></title>
    <link href="https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/07/12/Async-nodejs-API-server-testing/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-12T01:20:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://rollbar.com/blog/post/2013/07/12/Async-nodejs-API-server-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is about how we built our test suite for our API server at <a href="http://rollbar.com/">Rollbar</a> and some of the tricks and gotchas we ran into along the way. We wanted to build a test suite that not only tested the API logic, but also the underlying code, namely the <a href="http://expressjs.com/">Express</a> and the <a href="http://www.senchalabs.org/connect/">Connect</a> middlewares we use. If our API server was going to break, we wanted to know before we deployed it to thousands of customers and millions of requests per day.</p>

<p>Testing is super important. If you don't want to test, this probably won't be very helpful or interesting.</p>

<h2>We use Vows. Why not Mocha?</h2>

<p><a href="http://visionmedia.github.io/mocha/">Mocha</a> is, by far, the most widely used testing framework for Node.js apps. So, why didn't we use it? The two main reasons were that Vows was the first thing I found when Googling "nodejs async testing" and the other is that the syntax of Mocha tests felt like another language and less like code. Mocha tests are more readble but the benefit of readability was overshadowed by the need to remember all of these new, special-case methods that Mocha injects.</p>

<p><code>javascript
//Mocha
[1,2,3].indexOf(5).should.equal(-1);
</code></p>

<p>vs</p>

<p><code>javascript
//Vows
assert.equal([1,2,3].indexOf(5), -1);
</code></p>

<p>There's something that bothered me about the former. I didn't like how the library used a bunch of magic to enable something this small/strange.</p>

<p>Mocha has a lot of awesome features but none that were important enough for me to switch.</p>

<h2>A simple Vows test</h2>

<p>Vows works just as you'd expect it to, except when it doesn't. More on that later…</p>

<p>``` javascript
var vows = require('vows');
var assert = require('assert');
vows.describe('testmodule').addBatch({
  "call username() with a valid user id": {</p>

<pre><code>topic: function() {
  var callback = this.callback;
  return username(42, this.callback);
},
"and verify username is correct": function(err, username) {
  assert.isNull(err);
  assert.isString(username);
  assert.equal(username, "cory");
}
</code></pre>

<p>  }
}).export(module, {error: false});
```</p>

<p>The above test will make sure that the function <code>username()</code> calls its callback with <code>(null, "cory")</code>.</p>

<p>Note that we use this.callback since everything is assumed to be async and we use <code>{error: false}</code> when we export the batch. More on those later.</p>

<p>Check out the Vows <a href="http://vowsjs.org/">website</a> for better examples.</p>

<h2>Useful design patterns (I swear this will be short)</h2>

<p>We've found a few idioms and conventions that have been super helpful. Without going too much into design patterns and architecture, here are a few tips that have made writing tests super-easy; almost enjoyable—almost.</p>

<h3>Separate your view logic from your API business logic</h3>

<p>Your server's views should have one job, to marshall data from the request/socket/carrier pigeon and provide it to your API library.</p>

<p>Any error checking done in your views should be to make sure the types provided to your API library are correct.</p>

<h3>Make every function you write use a callback.</h3>

<p>This is super-important for refactoring and adding new features. If you find yourself wanting to add a feature that requires i/o into a code path that was assumed to be completely synchonous, you'll need to refactor the hell our of your code to make it work. Don't bother. Make everything take a callback. Embrace async!</p>

<h3>Make the first argument to <em>every</em> callback be an optional error.</h3>

<p>This is how the Node.js developers do it and I agree. It makes for a lot more boiler-plate code but it forces you to keep error handling in-mind when developing. Writing defensive code is more important than writing fewer lines of code.</p>

<p>This will also make testing much, much easier with Vows. How? Read on…</p>

<h2>Testing the API server, for reals</h2>

<p>Definitely write tests and exercise your API library directly but don't stop there. Fork a process, start your API server up in it and start firing requests at it using Vows.</p>

<p>testcommon.js:</p>

<p>``` javascript
exports.initTestingAppChildProc = function(config, promise) {
  // ... Setup temporary config file
  // ... Get path to your main app.js
  // ... Initialize the api library</p>

<p>  // fork a child process to start the api server
  var args = [configPath, 'test'];
  var appProc = fork(appJsPath, args);</p>

<p>  // This is used to tell if our API server died during its
  // initialization.
  var pendingCallback = true;</p>

<p>  appProc.on('message', function(message) {</p>

<pre><code>if (message == 'ready') {
  pendingCallback = false;

  // This is how we know our API server is ready to 
  // receive requests. The message is emitted in the
  // API server once it's ready to receive requests.
  promise.emit('success', null, appProc);
}
</code></pre>

<p>  });
  appProc.on('exit', function(code, signal) {</p>

<pre><code>if (pendingCallback) {
  var msg = 'child process exited before callback';
  console.error(msg);
  promise.emit('error', new Error(msg));
}
</code></pre>

<p>  });
  appProc.on('SIGTERM', function() {</p>

<pre><code>process.exit();
</code></pre>

<p>  });
};
```</p>

<p>In our API server:</p>

<p>``` javascript
// initialize the API and start the web server when it's ready
api.init(config, function(err) {
  if (err) {</p>

<pre><code>log.error('Could not initialize API: ' + err);
process.exit(1);
</code></pre>

<p>  } else {</p>

<pre><code>// Start up the server
var httpServer = app.listen(port, host, function() {
  log.info('API server is ready.');
  log.info('Listening on ' + host + ':' + port);

  // Use the "ready" message to signal that the server is ready.
  // This is used by the test suite to wait for the api server
  // process to start up before sending requests.
  if (process.send) {
    process.send('ready');
  }
});
</code></pre>

<p>  }
});
```</p>

<p>tests/routes.project.js:</p>

<p>``` javascript
vows.describe('routes.project').addBatch({
  // Provides a reference to the api server child process
  'Start up an API server': {</p>

<pre><code>topic: function() {
  var promise = new events.EventEmitter();
  common.initTestingAppChildProc(config, promise);
  return promise;
},
teardown: function(err, childProc) {
  var callback = this.callback;
  var shutdown = function() {
    api.shutdown(callback);
  };
  if (childProc) {
    childProc.on('exit', function(code, sig) {
      shutdown();
    });
    childProc.kill();
  } else {
    shutdown();
  }
},
'and get a valid project': {
  topic: function(err, childProc) {
    common.apiGet(url('api/1/project/',
        {access_token: config.test.validEnabledReadAccessToken}), this.callback);
  },
  'returns 200 OK': common.assertStatus(200),
  'returns JSON': common.assertJsonContentType(),
  'fast local response time': common.assertMaxResponseTime(20),
  "returns a valid api response": common.assertValidApiResponse(),
  "has a result key in the JSON response": common.assertJsonHasFields(['result']),
  "there's no api error": common.assertNoApiError(),
  'all of the deploy fields are available': common.assertJsonHasFields(db.projectFields(),
      'result'),
  'cross-check account id with api.getAccount': {
    topic: function(err, resp, body) {
      var project = body.result;
      api.getAccount(body.result.account_id, this.callback);
    },
    'verify the account is not null': function(err, account) {
      assert.isNull(err);      
      assert.isObject(account);         
    }       
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>}).export(module, {error: false});
```</p>

<p>There is a lot happening in these tests.</p>

<ul>
<li>We use promises to notify our test when the API server is ready.

<ul>
<li>Documentation for using promises with Vows can be found <a href="http://vowsjs.org/#-writing-asynchronous-tests">here</a>.</li>
<li>I'm not completely on-board with the Promise design pattern but it seemed like the easiest way to get this working. Mostly, I needed an event to be fired when there was an error that caused the API server process to shut down.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>We use a Vows teardown function to shut down the API server process.</li>
<li>We use our API library to help test our API server.

<ul>
<li>We cross-check our API server's response by using our API library directly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>We use Vows macros for reusable tests on all API requests.

<ul>
<li>We also make use of Vows contexts even though there are none in this example.</li>
<li>Documentation for macros and contexts are <a href="http://vowsjs.org/#-macros">here</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Gotchas</h2>

<p>Never, ever, ever throw an uncaught exception in a Vows topic. It makes debugging impossible. I've wasted hours looking through my API library for a bug only to find that I had a silly bug in my topic.</p>

<p>Always use <code>export(module, {error: false})</code> in your Vows batches. This option is not really described in the Vows docs. I had to find it in the source. Basically, if you don't have this, Vows will inspect the first argument to each test to see if it's an error. Vows will potentially call your test functions with a different set of arguments depending on if the first parameter to the topic's callback is an Error or not. It's completely strange and magical and <a href="https://github.com/cloudhead/vows/pull/263">confusing</a>.</p>

<p>Testing without mock objects means that you need a real database which means you probably need real-ish data to test with. This is tough. We chose to maintain a DB SQL fixture that we have to update whenever the schema changes. It's a bit clunky but it works. I'm open to suggestions for this if anyone knows of a better way.</p>

<h2>Wrapping up…</h2>

<p>We use <a href="http://circleci.com">CircleCI</a> to run all of these tests and are really happy with their service. It's fast and easy to set up. Also, it has all of the systems that our API server uses like MySQL, Beanstalkd and Memcache pre-installed. This gets us closer to testing in a production environment than would otherwise be possible.</p>

<p>Hopefully you were able to glean some useful tips from our experience at <a href="http://rollbar.com/">Rollbar</a>. We love building tools for devs like you!</p>

<p>Add me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/coryvirok">@coryvirok</a>.
Follow <a href="https://twitter.com/rollbar">@rollbar</a> for more updates.</p>

<h2>Moment of zen</h2>

<p><code>
✓ OK » 497 honored (33.232s)
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
